Francisco Rafael Uicab Cox

FRONTEND / WEB DEVELOPER

Email: francisco.rc.uicab@gmail.com Phone: (+52) 999 4587266

Location: Mérida, Yucatán, México

SUMMARY

Software developer with +5 years of professional experience, working mainly with frontend technologies for the web, specially with Javascript libraries and frameworks and Wordpress. A quick-learner and an adaptive developer. I am committed to making client's visions come true.

TECHNOLOGIES

HTML	css	SASS / LES	S Javaso	cript A	ngular	React	Wordpress	jQuery	PHP
Typescrip	ot Git	UI/UX	MySQL	NodeJS	Fire	ebase			

EXPERIENCE

Advancio - Software Development Engineer

JUN 2021 - APR 2023

- Create, maintain and develop updates for websites powered by Wordpress, Squarespace and Webflow.
- Work on a React JS project and work with an experienced team of developers, on SCRUM.

DaCodes - Web Developer

DECEMBER 2017 - MAY 2021

- Create, maintain and develop updates for Wordpress and Shopify websites.
- Work on emerging Angular projects together with a team of back-end developers.
- Improve SEO and optimization for existing websites, greatly increasing their exposure through the most popular web engines and improving their loading speed.

OTHER SKILLS

- Word, PowerPoint and Excel (The basic Office package).
- Good knowledge of UI/UX. And well aware of the importance of responsive design.
- Basic-use experience with Illustrator and Gimp/Photoshop.
- Experience with Unity (for personal projects), which also means: 3D modeling and C#.
- Visual expression of ideas. I have found it incredibly underrated and much needed.

LANGUAGES

English - Advanced (C1)

I use it in everyday activities and, of course, professionally.

French - Intermediate (B1)

Spoken for a whole year while studying in France.

Spanish - Native

Embedded in my default settings.

EDUCATION

IUT de Tarbes

Digital Communication and Webmastering 2016 - 2017 | Tarbes, France

Universidad Tecnológica Metropolitana

Multimedia & E-Commerce 2014 - 2016 | Mérida, Yucatán, México